Barry Moser Papers
© 2005 University of Connecticut
- Series I: Projects, 1968-1998
  - Mother Goose Collection
    - (Children's Health Fund) - correspondence, design notes, photocopies from The Real Mother Goose (ill. by Blanche Fisher Wright), literature folder from Children's Health Fund, 1990 (Box 22:, Folder 1)
  - The Mushroom Man
    - Jacket proofs (variant designs), correspondence, design notes, 2 MS copies (with design notes), early type proof for title lettering, concept art copies, concept photo, 7 pcs. prelim. pencil sketches, 1992-1993 (Box 6:, Folder 1)
    - Galley set with corrections, type proof, concept art copy, 1 pc. prelim. pencil sketch, 2 pcs. layout and design sheets, 1992-1993 (Box 6:, Folder 2)
  - My Cats Nick and Nora
    - Correspondence, MS copies, design notes, set of folded and gathered leaves with jacket, 1994-1995 (Box 8:, Folder 1)
    - Correspondence, concept photos, clippings, copies of concept art, preliminary design paste-ups, 1994-1995 (Box 8:, Folder 2)
    - 2 galley sets, type proofs, 1 pc. prelim. pencil sketch, 1 pc. prelim. line drawing on tracing paper, layout notes, copies of concept photos in prelim. paste-up, 1994-1995 (Box 8:, Folder 3)
  - My Dog Rosie
    - Correspondence, jacket copy text title lettering designs, dummy (copy of pencil sketch dummy pages pasted to 8.5 × 11 paper, with corrections), copy of later dummy featuring concept art copies and paste-in text, 1993-1994 (Box 6:, Folder 1)
      (reduced size)
    - 1 prelim. pencil sketch, copies of concept art and concept photos, many copies on transparency stock, 1993-1994 (Box 6:, Folder 2)
    - Cover design paste-up and cover design proof, “pawprint” ornament paste-up, full-size dummy with paste-in text and concept art copies (includes corrections), 1993-1994 (Box 6:, Folder 3)
    - Lettering/cover layout sheets, color galley set with one paste-in alteration, copy of galley set with minor corrections, jacket proof, 1993-1994 (Box 6:, Folder 4)
  - Noah's Cats and the Devil's Fire
    - 4 pencil sketches, 1 watercolor, 1991 (Box 2:, Folder 1)
      (complement to pencil sketch), correspondence, MS copy, various lettering and calligraphy designs
  - Odyssey Classics: A White Romance, Justice and Her Brothers, Dustland, The Gathering
    - Correspondence, 5 pcs. pencil sketch drawings, copies of concept art, clippings, promotional materials, photocopies of finished art, ca.1989 (Box 18:, Folder 1)
  - On Call Back Mountain
    - Correspondence, 5 MS copies (various dates), type samples, MS copy with Moser's illustration ideas inserted, 1996 (Box 10:, Folder 1)
    - 8 pcs. prelim. pencil sketches on transparency stock, “thumbnail” book design sheet, 1 pc. prelim. pencil sketch of house, copies of prelim. art, paste-up of original “Scholastic” logo, dummy with paste-in text and photocopied full size art (some corrections), 1996 (Box 10:, Folder 2)
    - 2 sets folded and gathered leaves with jacket proofs, proof for book poster (50% size), 1996-97 (Box 10:, Folder 3)
    - Concept art for jacket, jacket proof (w/ corrections), color copy of jacket proof, copy of jacket proof, photocopy of galley set (with text), 1996-1997 (Box 10:, Folder 4)
    - 2 pcs. uncut color galley sheets (art only, no text), 1996-1997 (Box 10:, Folder 5)
  - Our New Puppy
    - Miniature dummy w/ paste-in concept art and text, lettering study, 1 pc. prelim. pencil sketch, concept art copies, design notes, MS copies, type proofs, 1995 (Box 10:, Folder 1)
    - Dummy w/ paste-in text and paste-in art copies, 1 pc. “pawprint” design on transparency paper, 1995 (Box 10:, Folder 2)
    - 2 sets color galleys, jacket proof, copy of galley set, copy of type proofs, 1 pc. concept art collage, 1995-1996 (Box 10:, Folder 3)
  - Pilgrim's Progress
    - Correspondence, contract, library search data, research articles, design notes, text format samples with corrections, 1993-1994 (Box 7:, Folder 1)
    - Print of “sword” engraving, copy of “sword” engraving, layout and design notes, lettering samples, hand-lettered “I” design, font sample books for fonts “Charlemagne” and “Trajan”, 1993-1994 (Box 7:, Folder 2)
    - 8 pcs. watercolor art (some designs incomplete, art apparently not used in final version), ca. 1993 (Box 7:, Folder 3)
    - 3 pcs. prelim. pencil sketches, clippings, copies of concept art, copies of photos, 1993-1994 (Box 7:, Folder 4)
    - Text copy (2 col., no ill., laser printed?), ca. 1993 (Box 7:, Folder 5)
    - 3 versions of “front matter” text (no ill.), 2 partial text copies (no ill.), 1993-1994 (Box 7:, Folder 6)
    - Early MS typescript (one column), ca. 1993 (Box 7:, Folder 7)
    - 2 text copies (showing minor corrections), partial text copy (no paging) with spaces inserted for illustrations, partial text copy, 1993-1994 (Box 7:, Folder 8)
    - Dummy with text paste-in and corrections (no illustrations), ca. 1993 (Box 7:, Folder 9)
    - Dummy [earlier than folder 9] with text paste-in, corrections, and some illustration notes, ca. 1993 (Box 7:, Folder 10)
    - Layout and design sheets, color copy of jacket design, proofs for possible endpapers (?), concept art copies for cover design, 1993-1994 (Box 7:, Folder 11)
  - Polly Vaughn
    - Correspondence, design notes, 3 sets type proofs (one set w/ corrections), 1991-1992 (Box 2:, Folder 1)
    - 1 pc. watercolor art (not finished), 1 pc. prelim. pencil sketch, 1 pc. prelim. art, lettering studies and calligraphy samples, 1 pc. paste-up for title lettering, 1 pc. paste-up for “Afterword”, 1 pc. paste-up for initial “P”, 1 pc. paste-up for snowflake ornament, dummy w/ paste-in text and color art proofs (some corrections), 1991-92 (Box 2:, Folder 2)
    - 7 sets MS typescipts (some are copies, some contain corrections, one has “post-it notes” with editorial comments, some sets have variant title Polly), 1991-1992 (Box 2:, Folder 3)
    - Clippings, correspondence, lettering samples, and two proof sets - one is marked with corrections and the other, corrected proof is marked “duplicate”, 1991-1992 (Box 2:, Folder 4)
    - Layout design page, uncut galley proofs, various alternate proofs for endpapers, jacket proofs, 1992 (Box 2:, Folder 5)
  - A Prayer for the Opening of Little League Season
    - 10 pcs. original ornament “drop cap.” letters, various color copies of drop cap. letters, two copies on transparency of drop cap. initials, lettering and type design samples, 1 pc. copy from dummy, 1 pc. color copy from proof, 1994-1995 (Box 11:, Folder 1)
    - Programs from the 1993 “North Jackson Youth Babseball” opening ceremony, “NJYB” rosters for 1993, clippings, copies of concept art photos, early concept art collage pieces, 1993-1995 (Box 11:, Folder 2)
    - Correspondence, prelim. dummy (8.5×11) with thumbnail sketches, working dummy with color art copies and text paste-in (includes correction notes), type proof, photos, plane ticket, 1994-1995 (Box 11:, Folder 3)
    - 5 pcs. partial watercolor art (rejected/unfinished), 1 pc. color copy, 1994-1995 (Box 11:, Folder 4)
  - Prayers from the Ark
    - Publication of text (Penguin edition) from 1976, correspondence, dummy with paste-in text and paste-in illustrations (with corrections), 2 sets folded and gathered leaves with jacket proofs (one set with corrections), color copies of prelim. jacket designs, concept art copies, photocopies of illustrations, lettering studies, 1976-1992 (Box 18:, Folder 1)
  - A Ring of Tricksters
    - Correspondence, MS typescript (laserprint?), 1997 (Box 24:, Folder 1)
    - Dummy with paste-in proof copies (text + art), various sections of earlier (?) dummy, ca. 1997 (Box 24:, Folder 2)
    - Approx. 60 pcs. prelim. pencil sketches, copies of concept art, ca. 1997 (Box 24:, Folder 3)
    - Correspondence, 2 pcs. watercolor art (one unfinished), layout notes, proofs for front-end mataerial, color copy of preliminary jacket design, concept art copies, copies of pencil sketches, folder labeled `additional research' containing copied alternate versions of stories, 5 pcs. jacket proofs (some variant designs), 2 pcs. color art galleys, ca. 1997 (Box 24:, Folder 4)
    - Various galley copies (incomplete set?) with text and art, 1997 (Box 24:, Folder 5)
    - Color galley proof set (facing page art not cut), color study proof, proof sheet for “Tricksters” lettering, 12 pcs. various color proofs (on glossy paper), 1997 (Box 24:, Folder 6)
  - Shiloh Season
    - Correspondence, jacket proofs, contract copy, 1996-1997 (Box 20:, Folder 1)
    - MS typescript, ca. 1994 (Box 20:, Folder 2)
    - Correspondence, MS typescript, 1994 (Box 20:, Folder 3)
    - MS typescript, ca. 1994 (Box 20:, Folder 4)
  - Sky Dogs
    - Correspondence, MS typescript, dummy with paste-in text and paste-in illustration copies, photocopy of galley proof(?), 1989-1991 (Box 15:, Folder 1)
    - Title lettering studies, copies of concept photos/clippings, ca.1991 (Box 15:, Folder 2)
    - Various color art proofs marked with corrections, set of color art copies, ca.1991 (Box 15:, Folder 3)
    - Set of color art transparencies, layout design sheets, ca.1991 (Box 15:, Folder 4)
  - St. Jerome and the Lion
    - Correspondence, 4 pcs. rough sketch cover designs (color), concept copy photos, lettering designs, concept art copies, ornament designs, 1990 (Box 23:, Folder 1)
    - Dummy w/ paste-in text and paste-in color art proofs, photocopy dummy, 2 sets MS typescripts (variant, one with typesetting notes), copy of MS as sent to printer, 2 sets type proofs, ca. 1990 (Box 23:, Folder 2)
    - 2 pcs. original watercolor art (not used in final art?), layout and design notes, study for title lettering, ca. 1990 (Box 23:, Folder 3)
    - Original pencil sketch (matted and mounted) donated to NCLC in 1992, ca. 1990 (Box 23:, Folder 4)
  - Tales of Edgar Allen Poe
    - Correspondence, 1988-1991 (Box 16:, Folder 1)
    - Galley type proof (no ill.)(with corrections), ca.1991 (Box 16:, Folder 2)
    - Jacket proof, set of color art proofs, type proofs for stories “omitted” in this edition, 1991 (Box 16:, Folder 3)
  - Their Eyes Were Watching God
    - Correspondence, lettering samples, layout design notes (includes copies of various prelim. art sketches), page format sheet, photocopies of finished art, 1991 (Box 20:, Folder 1)
  - Through the Mickle Woods
    - Correspondence, MS copy, font sample with overlays/corrections?, lettering design and paste-ups (for title), type proofs, 1990-1992 (Box 5:, Folder 1)
    - Contract, dummy with pencil design sketches and type paste-in, 1 pc. type paste-up(?), concept copies for type and ornament design, 1990-1992 (Box 5:, Folder 2)
    - Jacket proof copies with corrections, layout and design notes, partial set of art galleys, jacket proof, galley photocopies (one set + additional copies) with corrections, 1990-1992 (Box 5:, Folder 3)
  - The Tinderbox
    - 7 sets MS typescripts by Moser (3 set w/ visible corrections), copies of earlier translations of text, 1989 (Box 19:, Folder 1)
    - Correspondence, MS typescript, copies of concept photos, longhand MS for afterword, typescript copies (w/ corrections), 2 sets type proofs, lettering and layout studies, 1987-1990 (Box 19:, Folder 2)
    - Approx. 9 pcs. prelim. pencil sketches (most very rough), ill. design notes, copies of concept art, clippings, issue of Appalachia magazine from 1989 (used for concept art), 1989-1990 (Box 19:, Folder 3)
    - Dummy with paste-in text and paste-in art proofs (with corrections), set of folded and gathered galley proofs (color), 1989-1990 (Box 19:, Folder 4)
    - Jacket proof, prelim. paste-up design for jacket, transparency pieces for shooting jacket art, postcards based on jacket art, layout design sheets, ca. 1990 (Box 19:, Folder 5)
  - The Trojan War and the Adventures of Odysseus
    - Correspondence, copies of jacket design, 10 pcs. prelim. pencil sketches of “Trojan Horse” design, copies of art, set of color copies of art galleys, layout design sheet, 1996 (Box 10:, Folder 1)
  - Tucker Pfeffercorn
    - Correspondence, 2 MS type copies (one w/ extensive corrections), set of typed “rough proofs” (laserprint?), dummy with text paste-in and thumbnail pencil sketches, 1993-1994 (Box 14:, Folder 1)
    - MS type copy (with corrections), 1 pc. water-color design (letter “o”), clippings, copies of concept art, copies of font samples, folder with text fragments pasted into cover, ca. 1993-1994 (Box 14:, Folder 2)
    - 4 sets of typed “rough proofs” (one has design notes, another is marked “final MS 10/13”), ca. 1993-1994 (Box 14:, Folder 3)
    - Type proof, layout and design sheets, jacket copy proof sheets, 1 pc. color art proof, color jacket proof, color jacket proof marked “2nd proof”, 10 pcs. color art proofs marked “second proof”, ca. 1993-1994 (Box 14:, Folder 4)
  - Turtle Island ABC
    - Various type proof sheets (pages out of order) with corrections, 1992-1994 (Box 12:, Folder 1)
    - Correspondence, contracts, 1992-1993 (Box 12:, Folder 2)
    - Dummy with paste-in text (some concept copy illustrations and design notes), partial type proof, 2 type proof sets (one with corrections), 1992-1993 (Box 12:, Folder 3)
    - 2 type proof sets, MS type copy, copy of MS typescript marked “revision”, font size sample copies, 1992-1993 (Box 12:, Folder 4)
    - 4 type proof sets, 1992-1993 (Box 12:, Folder 5)
    - 3 pcs. color layout design paste-ups (with color art copies, background paper, and overlays with horizontal lines replacing text), ca. 1993 (Box 12:, Folder 6)
  - Unidentified Materials (Box 24)
    - Production Materials
      - Blank booklet (cut and bound), various concept copies, undated (Box 25:, Folder 1)
        (book project not determined)
    - Color Transparencies
      - Transparencies for book projects including Polly Vaughn, Tales of Edgar Allen Poe, Appalachia, Little Tricker, and at least one of the Jump! books, ca. 1987-1992 (Box 25:, Folder 1)
    - Correspondence
      - Correspondence not related to specific book projects, unidentified engraving copies, and a MS essay by Moser entitled “Roosevelt”, 1990-1994 (Box 25:, Folder 1)
    - Publications
      - National Directory of Storytelling (1992), David R. Godine Publishing Catalogs (1990, 1988), copy of promotional literature for Sony CVP-G700 color video printer (1992), 1988-1992 (Box 25:, Folder 1)
  - What You Know First
    - Clippings, copies of concept art photos/copies, 4 pcs. photos, 1 pc. partial pencil sketch with concept copy, 2 pcs. concept copies on transparency stock *note - collection shipped with sample of cottonwood leaves, including branch used as basis for jacket back design, 1994-1995 (Box 11:, Folder 1)
    - Correspondence, set of folded and gathered leaves with jacket proof, jacket “first proof”, early dummy with text paste-in and some pencil thumbnails, type proof, 1994-1995 (Box 11:, Folder 2)
    - Test printings of engravings (some on different papers/stocks), 1994-1995 (Box 11:, Folder 3)
    - Design and layout sheets, prelim. jacket design, 3 variant proofs for broadside advertisement, 1994-1995 (Box 11:, Folder 4)
  - When Birds Could Talk and Bats Could Sing
    - 2 MS copies, 1994 (Box 26:, Folder 1)
    - Dummy set with paste-in text and copied art proofs, ca. 1995 (Box 26:, Folder 2)
      (some corrections)
    - Correspondence, concept art copies, design notes, copy of jacket galley, 1994-1995 (Box 26:, Folder 3)
    - Correspondence, lettering studies, concept art copies, 5 pcs. prelim. pencil sketches, 1994-1995 (Box 26:, Folder 4)
    - Set of color galley proofs (folded and gathered) with jacket proof, set of 2nd proofs (not cut or gathered) interleaved with select type mechanicals (set includes jacket proof), 1995 (Box 26:, Folder 5)
    - Set of color art galleys (1st proofs) interleaved with select type mechanicals (set includes jacket proof), 1995 (Box 26:, Folder 6)
    - 2 sets type proofs (with working title Still and Ugly Bat), 1995 (Box 26:, Folder 7)
    - 30 pcs. prelim. pencil sketches (on transparency paper), 1 pc. jacket prelim. pencil skech, layout and design sheets, lettering studies, 1 pc. watercolor prelim. (sky background), concept art copies, 1 pc. paste-up (on cardboard) prelim. letter design, 1 pc. paste-up ornament design, 1 pc. paste-up title lettering (on cardboard), 1994-95 (Box 26:, Folder 8)
  - When Willard Met Babe Ruth
    - Correspondence, design notes and “shooting schedule,” 13 pcs. illustration “thumbnails” with handwritten descriptions, type proof revised copies, 1994-1995 (Box 8:, Folder 1)
    - 2 MS typed copies (with corrections, one marked “latest”), type proof, copy of early dummy with text and text descriptions in place of illustrations, copy of later dummy with rough sketches, 1994-1995 (Box 8:, Folder 2)
    - 2 pcs. pencil sketches on transparency stock, 3 pcs. line drawings on transparency stock (cover ill. designs), copies of alt. cover designs, copies of concept photos, prelim. art paste-ups using concept art photos, 1994-1995 (Box 8:, Folder 3)
    - Dummy with paste-in text and copies of b/w art, photocopy of dummy (sized and cut as dummy) larger size dummy with handwritten ill. Descriptions, 1994-1995 (Box 8:, Folder 4)
    - Copy of galley set, layout and design sheets, type sample galleys (2 pcs.), 1 pc. design collage with photocopy concept art, 1994-1996 (Box 8:, Folder 5)
  - Whistling Dixie
    - Color art proofs (“first proofs”), three preliminary pencil sketches, storyboard overview page, dummy with numerous pencil thumbnail sketches, 1992 (Box 3:, Folder 1)
    - Correspondence, typed MS, copies of concept photos, copied preliminary sketches, 1992 (Box 3:, Folder 2)
    - 4 watercolor pieces (background washes?), 4 watercolor lettering samples, 1992 (Box 3:, Folder 3)
    - Art proofs (mainly backgrounds, no text), layout and design pages, 3 watercolor title lettering samples, lettering transparencies, 1 prelim. pencil sketch, 1992 (Box 3:, Folder 4)
  - Associated Materials
    - Various Agreements and Contracts, including:, 1982-1993 (Box 28)
      - The Adventures of Sherlock Holmes
      - Alice's Adventures in Wonderland
      - American Girl and “untitled work”
      - And Still the Turtle Watched
      - Appalachia: The Voices of Sleeping Birds
      - Around the World in 80 Days, Tales of Edgar Allan Poe
      - The Ballad of Biddy Early
      - Barry Moser Engagement Calendar 1992
      - Beauty and the Beast
      - The Collected Tales of Jahdu (Ali Jahdu Storybook?)
      - Dr. Jekyll and Mr. Hyde
      - East of the Sun and West of the Moon
      - Fanny and Eddie Underground
      - Frankenstein
      - The Ghost Horse of the Mounties, Alice in Wonderland
      - Huckleberry Finn
      - “I Remember Grandpa”
      - In the Beginning
      - Jump: The Adventures of Br'er Rabbit
      - Jump Again!
      - Jump on Over!
      - Kasthanka
      - Little Tricker the Squirrel
      - The Magic Wood
      - “Mother Goose” poster
      - The New Revised Standard Bible
      - Polly Vaughn
      - Prayers from the Ark
      - A River Runs Through It
      - The Robber Bridegroom
      - The Scarlet Letter, The Red Badge of Courage
      - Sky Dogs
      - Song of Songs
      - Sook's Cookbook
        - Tales by Washington Irving
      - St. Jerome and the Lion
      - Through the Mickle Woods
      - The Tinderbox
      - Tucker Pfeffercorn
      - “Untitled Folk Tale”
      - The Wonderful Wizard of Oz
    - Various Color Transparencies (in labeled envelopes), including:, ca. 1987-1992
      - And Still the Turtle Watched
      - Appalachia: The Voices of Sleeping Birds, (2 envelopes)
      - Around the World in Eighty Days
      - The Ballad of Biddy Early
      - Casey
      - East of the Sun and West of the Moon, (2 envelopes)
      - In the Beginning, (2 envelopes)
      - Jump on Over
      - Kashtanka
      - Little Tricker the Squirrel
      - Odyssey Series Covers
      - Sky Dogs
      - Sook's Cookbook
      - St. Jerome and the Lion, (2 envelopes)
      - Tales of Edgar Allan Poe
      - The Tinderbox, (2 envelopes)
      - Tom Sawyer, (2 envelopes)
    - Folder of Unidentified Transparencies
    - Folder labeled “Tom Sawyer - State of Calligraphy” - 1 pc. calligraphy paste-up
    - "Woodcut by Barry Moser of Billie M. Levy in honor of her 80th birthday,", 2008 May 2